Guide to the Ella Winter Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Ella Winter Papers
1913-1978.
Winter, Ella.
41 boxes, 1 oversize folder
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library. 535 West 114th St., New York, NY, 10027.
4079487
History
Writer. Ella Winter (1898-1980) whose full name was Leonore Sophie Winter Steffens Stewart, was an economist by training and journalist by profession. She was married to Lincoln Steffens, and after his death, to screenwriter and playwright Donald Ogden Stewart.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, documents, notes, photographs, and printed material of Winter. The papers cover primarily the years after 1952 when she and Stewart settled in England to avoid involvement in the House Un-American Activities Committee investigations. Winter traveled widely in Russia, visited China in 1958, and spent nine months in Ghana in 1965. Her journeys are well documented in this collection. Among the manuscripts are drafts for many of her periodical articles, typescripts of her autobiography And Not to Yield, and articles written about her travels. Also, files on art, the labor movement in California, Robinson Jeffers, the McCarthy era, Lincoln Steffens, and Vietnam. There are numerous photographs taken on her trips abroad, including her work with the Friends of Austria, 1920, of many theatrical productions, and of her family and home. Because of her eclectic interests she was acquainted with many prominent individuals in politics, literature, theatre, and the arts. Among the major correspondents are Edward Albee, Charles and Oona Chaplin, W.E.B. Du Bois, Katharine Hepburn, Carey McWilliams, Kwame Nkrumah, Sean O'Casey, and Muriel Rukeyser.
Selected materials are cataloged, the remainder are arranged. The collection is arranged into seven series and several subseries:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
Series III: Uncataloged Correspondence
Series IV: Manuscripts
Subseries IV.1: And Not To Yield
Subseries IV.2: Articles--General
Subseries IV.3: Subjects
Subseries IV.3.1: China
Subseries IV.3.2: U.S.S.R.
Subseries IV.3.3: Ghana
Subseries IV.3.4: Charlie Chaplin
Subseries IV.3.5: Modern African Art
Subseries IV.4: Miscellaneous, Documents
Series V: Subject Files
Series VI: Photographs and Miscellaneous
Series VII: Printed Material
Subjects
Steffens, Lincoln, 1866-1936.; Stewart, Donald Ogden, 1894-1980.; Jeffers, Robinson, 1887-1962.; Albee, Edward, 1928-; Chaplin, Charlie, 1889-1977.; Du Bois, W. E. B. (William Edward Burghardt), 1868-1963.; Hepburn, Katharine, 1907-2003.; McWilliams, Carey, 1905-1980.; Nkrumah, Kwame, 1909-1972.; O'Casey, Sean, 1880-1964.; Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-1980.; Vietnam--Politics and government.; Soviet Union--Description and travel.; Ghana--Description and travel.; China--Description and travel.; Art.; Art, Modern--20th century--Africa; Labor movement--California.; Communism--United States.; Literature.; Arts.; Theater.; Photoprints.; Journalists.
The following boxes are located off-site: 3-41. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1980 M-80, Estate of Ella Winter, Gift
01/08/1998, M-01-08-98, Justin Kaplan corr. re. Steffens, Gift of Justin Kaplan
7/27/2011, M-2011-2012-M020, Boxes 32-41, Jarndyce Antiquarian Booksellers, Purchase
Selected Related Material-- at Columbia
Lincoln Steffens Papers, Rare Book & Manuscript Library.
Finding aid available in repository and online.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Albee, Edward (Box 1)
  - Bergman, Ingrid (Box 1)
  - Bliss, Sir Arthur (Box 1)
  - Brewster, Dorothy (Box 1)
  - Bridges, Harry (Box 1)
  - Brophy, Brigid (Box 1)
  - Caldwell, Erskine (Box 1)
  - Chaplin, Charles (Box 1)
  - Chaplin, Oona O'Neill (Mrs. Charles) (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Benjamin Victor (Box 1)
  - Deighton, Len (Box 1)
  - DuBois, Shirley Graham (Mrs. W.E.B.) (Box 1)
  - DuBois, William Edward Burghardt (Box 1)
  - Freeman, Joseph (Box 1)
  - Gilliatt, Penelope (Box 1)
  - Greene, Graham (Box 1)
  - Haldane, John Burdon Sanderson (Box 1)
  - Hepburn, Audrey (Box 1)
  - Hepburn, Katharine Houghton (Box 1)
  - Kerr, Deborah (Box 1)
  - Kollek, Teddy (Box 1)
  - LaFollette, Fola (Box 1)
  - Lamont, Cor1iss (Box 1)
  - Lamont, Helen Lamb (Mrs. Corliss) (Box 1)
  - Lardner, Ring, Jr. (Box 1)
  - Lewis, Oscar (Box 1)
  - Losey, Joseph (Box 1)
  - Mac Donald, Malcolm (Box 1)
  - McWilliams, Carrey (Box 1)
  - Mailer, Norman (Box 1)
  - Mills, C. Wright (Box 1)
  - Mitchison, Naomi (Box 1)
  - Needham, Joseph (Box 2)
  - Nkrumah, Kwame (Box 2)
  - O'Casey, Sean (Box 2)
  - Osborne, John (Box 2)
  - Roy, Claude (Box 2)
  - Rukey er, Muriel (Box 2)
  - Russell, Bertrand (Box 2)
  - Sarton, May (Box 2)
  - Schorer, Mark (Box 2)
  - Scofield, Paul (Box 2)
  - Shahn, Ben (Box 2)
  - Shaw, Irvin (Box 2)
  - Snow, Charles Percy Snow, Baron (Box 2)
  - Spock, Benjamin (Box 2)
  - Stead, Christina Ellen (Box 2)
  - Steffens, Lincoln (Box 2)
  - Stone, Isidor Feinstein (Box 2)
  - Strong, Anna Louise (Box 2)
  - Tynan, Elaine Brimberg (Mrs. Kenneth) (Box 2)
  - Tynan, K[enneth] (Box 2)
  - Ure, Mary (Box 2)
  - Von Wiegand, Charmion (Box 2)
  - Weigel, Helene (Mrs. Bertolt Brecht) (Box 2)
  - Williams, Albert Rhys (Box 2)
  - Worth, Irene (Box 2)
  - Wyzanski, Charles E., Jr. (Box 2)
- Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
  - Rukeyser, Muriel (Box 2)
  - Steffens, Lincoln (Box 2)
- Series III: Uncataloged Correspondence
  - A (Box 3, 32)
  - Aldridge, James and Dina (Box 3)
  - B (Box 3, 32)
  - Boudin, Leonard B. (Box 3)
  - Breacht, Bertolt-Estate/Berliner Ensemble (Box 3)
  - Brion, Francoise ("Looky") and family (Box 3)
  - C (Box 3, 32)
  - Cameron, Angus and Sheila (Box 3)
  - Collier, John G.S. (Box 3)
  - D (Box 3, 32)
  - Darcy, Sam and Emma (Box 3)
  - Davidson, Basil (Box 3)
  - Dobbs, Drs. Phyllis & Richard (Box 3)
  - Dunham, Barrows and Alice (Box 3)
  - E-F (Box 4, 32)
  - G (Box 4, 32)
  - H (Box 4, 32)
  - I-J (Box 4, 32)
  - K (Box 4, 32)
  - L (Box 4, 32)
  - Lloyd, Rosa Winter (Mrs. Harold) (Box 4)
  - Me (Box 4, 32)
  - M (Box 4, 32)
  - Martin, Josephine, M.D. Michialovski, Mira (Box 4)
  - Mitrany, Ena Limebeer (Box 4)
  - Moreuil, Rene, Foumy and family (Box 4)
  - N (Box 4, 32)
  - Nathan, Otto (Box 4)
  - O-P-Q (Box 4, 32)
  - R (Box 4, 32)
  - S (Box 5, 32)
  - Sayers, Michael (Box 5)
  - Shapiro, Herbert (see also: Subject Files/Steffens) (Box 5)
  - Steffens, Pete Stanley and family (Box 5, 32, 33)
  - Stewart, Ames (Box 5)
  - Stewart, Donald Ogden (Box 5, 33)
  - Stewart, Donald Ogden, Jr. and family (Box 5)
  - Suggett, Allen H. (Box 5)
  - T-U-V (Box 6, 33)
  - Telephone and Telegraph, Post Office-Correspondence about (Box 6)
  - Viertel, Salka and family (Box 6)
  - W (Box 6, 33)
  - Welch, Marie de L. (Box 6)
  - Wertham, Frederic, M.D. (Box 6)
  - Winter, Ella-outgoing letters (recipients unidentified) (Box 6)
  - Winter, Sylvia, and Charles Pollock (Box 6)
  - Wolfert, Ira, Helen and family (Box 6)
  - Wolff, Ernst and Thea Winter (Box 6)
  - Woodcock, Patrick (Box 6)
  - X-Y-Z (Box 6)
  - Dated correspondence (writers unknown), 1951-1978 (Box 6, 33)
  - Unidentified correspondence (writers and dates unknown) (Box 6, 33)
  - Envelopes, miscellaneous (Box 6)
- Series IV: Manuscripts
  - Subseries IV.1: And Not to Yield
    - Correspondence
      - General (Box 7)
      - Publishers (Box 7)
    - Notes (Box 7)
    - Publicity and Promotion (Box 7)
    - Reviews (Box 7)
    - Printed--miscellaneous (Box 7)
    - Draft typescript pages (Box 8-10)
    - Full typescript (Box 11)
  - Subseries IV.2: Articles--General
    - The American, by Henry James, dramatized by Ella Winter and Doris Lessing (Box 12)
    - Ask Dad--Outline, 1952 (Box 12)
    - The Baby Sitter (Box 12)
    - Beasts in Ancient, Primitive and Modern Art (Box 12)
    - The Bob A Job Gardeners (Box 34)
    - Bringing Up a Bush Baby (Box 34)
    - [The Bullitt Mission] (Box 12)
    - C.B.S. People's Platform (The Czechoslovakian Crisis, 1948 mimeograph) (Box 12)
    - [C. Wright Mills] (Box 12)
    - Children's Books in Eastern Germany (Box 12, 34)
    - Children's Dreams (Box 12)
    - Crags, Rocks and Wind [Life in Carmel, California] (Box 12)
    - A Day by the Soviet Sea (Box 34)
    - Diary, 1922 (Box 12)
    - Diary [of Therapy], 1960 and Undated (Box 12)
    - Ears to Hear (Box 12)
    - Easter Sunday (El Lissitzky), 1967 April 17 (Box 12)
    - The Emperor is Naked [Steffens and the Bullitt Mission] (Box 12, 34)
    - [Europe in 1947] (Lecture) (Box 12)
    - Evtushenko in England (Box 12)
    - The Farm Christmas, 1941 (Box 12)
    - Fenelon (Box 12)
    - Fifty Years on, 1972 (Box 12)
    - [Film on Arab-Israeli Coexistence]--Outline, 1971 (Box 12)
    - Flowers for Miss Weatherton, 1932 (Box 12)
    - The Gloves (Box 12)
    - Hollywood Wife (Box 12)
    - How to Diet (with notes and related items) (Box 12)
    - [Humour] (fragment) (Box 12)
    - Husbands (Box 12)
    - I Bought a Klee (Box 12, 34)
    - Is a World Government Forming (Box 34)
    - An Italian Emigrates (and other "Crispina" stories) (Box 12)
    - Just an Ordinary Morning (Box 12)
    - Lenin, Lincoln Steffens and the Women's Congress (Box 12)
    - London on a Bicycle (Box 12)
    - The Lost Tribes Find Themselves (Box 12)
    - Love in the Acquisitive Society (Box 12)
    - [Medicine-Chest Autobiography] (Box 13)
    - Men (For Wives) (Box 34)
    - [Mental Illness] (Box 13)
    - A Merry Christmas to our Trade Balance (also called "Centrepiece") (Box 13)
    - The Message (Box 34)
    - Modern British Theatre (Box 13)
    - Monkey in the House (and other "Peter the Monkey" stories) (Box 13)
    - My Monkey (Box 34)
    - National Committee for the Defence of Political Prisoners (Box 13)
      (with related material)
    - The New Germanys (Box 13)
    - The New Laundry (Box 13)
    - Nurses (Box 13)
    - [Play Reviews] (Box 13)
    - Plays (fragments) (Box 13)
    - The Question of John Steinbeck (Box 13)
    - Recent Changes in the U.S.S.R. (Box 34)
    - Recollections of Robinson Jeffers (Box 13)
    - [Reflections by Famous Individuals] (Box 13)
    - Reunion with an Empty Chair (Box 13)
      (with related items)
    - The Ring (Box 13)
    - [Sandberg, Willem] (Box 13)
    - Shoes for Sale (Box 34)
    - The Technician (Box 13)
    - Television Programs, Proposed--Outlines (Box 13)
    - Tooling for Inhumanity (Box 13)
    - Trust in Government (Box 13)
    - Voyage Through my Life--Book Outline, circa 1968 (Box 13)
    - We Must Hate (Box 13)
    - The Writers Club (Box 34)
    - A Woman for All Seasons [Helene Weigel-Mrs. Bert Brecht] (Box 13)
      (with photos)
    - [Various Short Stories] (Box 34)
  - Subseries IV.3: Subjects
    - Subseries IV.3.1: USSR
      (See Also: Series V: Subject Files)
      - Abstract Art in Realist Russia (Box 13)
      - How to Get Around Russia (Box 13)
      - I Spend a Summer at a Soviet Holiday Resort (Box 13)
      - Journal (Russia/China), 1958 (Box 41)
      - No Kissing in the Streets-No Shorts (Box 13)
      - Shopping in Soviet Russia, 1957 (Box 13)
        ("Perms and Puppets")
      - Soviet Children's Entertainment (Box 13)
      - Stalin, 1957 (Box 13)
      - Uncle Chukosha (Kornei Chukovsky) (Box 13)
      - [Victory Over the Sun] (Box 13)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
    - Subseries IV.3.2: China
      - Books
        - I Went to China--Typescript (Unpublished) (Box 14)
        - People All Together…A China Diary--Typescript (Unpublished) (Box 14)
      - Articles
        - After Hours: Entertainment in Red China (Box 15)
        - Any Questions (or "Where Everyone can Criticize") (Box 15)
        - The Burned Man (Box 15)
          (with related photos)
        - Business in the New China (Box 15)
        - China in the Anglo-American Press (Box 15)
        - China's New Human Beings: Training a Universal Person (Box 15)
        - Civilization Comes to Inner Mongolia (Box 15)
        - A Divorce Case in Red China (Box 15)
          (with related item)
        - An Ex-Concubine Runs a Collective (Box 15)
        - A Family in Peking (Box 15)
        - From Classroom into the Field (Box 15)
        - Hotel Life in Red China (Box 15)
        - How to Catch Rats, by Mrs. Tsao (or "How to Contribute to Society," with photographs and related items) (Box 15)
        - I Meet a Chinese Capitalist (Box 15)
        - Inner Mongolia Today (Box 15)
        - Inside Chinese Women: Attention: Women at Work (or "Some Chinese Women") (Box 15)
        - Inside Mao's China (Box 15)
        - Juvenile Non-Delinquents-Difficult Children in Peking (Box 15)
        - Lambs' Tails and Goats' Horns: Ways of Chinese Cookery (Box 15)
        - Ming Magnificence, 1958 (Box 15)
        - Ming Tomb Near Peking (Ting Tomb) (Box 15)
        - Mr. Cheng Leaps Forward (Box 15)
        - Mongolia (Box 15)
        - Notes on a Leap Forward (Box 15)
        - One Chinese Housewife (or "One Housewife's Story") (Box 15)
        - Outline for Radio Talk on China (Box 15)
        - Repentance, Inc. (Box 15)
        - Shopping in Peking (or "Shopping in China") (Box 15)
        - To a Publisher (Box 15)
        - Under Tea Wood: A Chinese Town Awakes (several alternate titles) (Box 15)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
      - Journal (Russia/China), 1958 (Box 41)
    - Subseries IV.3.3: Ghana
      - Africa is Hot (Box 16)
        (book, unpublished; includes many of the articles listed below)
      - Africa is Hot (Box 16)
        (Possible novelization)
      - Baskets, Baskets (Box 16)
      - Big Robert (Box 16)
      - Children (Box 16)
      - Economics (Box 16)
      - Emerging Nation (Box 16)
      - Gold Dust and Delight (Box 16)
      - Handicraft Exhibition (Box 16)
      - The Imprisoned Man in Ghana (Box 16)
      - King of Ashanti Prempeh II Rum (Box 16)
      - Leader of his People: Portrait of Kwame Nkrumah… (Box 16)
      - Little Robert (Box 16)
      - Modern African Art (Box 16)
      - My Relations with President Nkrumah (Box 16)
      - My Tropical Garden (Box 16)
      - My Work (Box 16)
      - Neighbors (Box 16)
      - The New Old Woman in Africa (Box 16)
      - O.A.U. September Conference in Accra (Box 16)
      - Nkrumah (Box 16)
      - Pawpaws and Pineapple, Mango and Make-do (Box 16)
      - Posters Show (Box 16)
      - Press and Propaganda (Box 16)
      - Setting up Socialism: State Industries in Ghana (or "Enterprising Ghana") (Box 16)
      - [The Silk Cotton Tree] (Box 16)
      - Television Students (Box 16)
      - What is Ghana Like (Box 16)
      - Fragments and Miscellaneous (Box 16)
    - Subseries IV.3.4: Charlie Chaplin
      - [The Chaplin Children] (Box 12)
      - Chaplin Notes (Box 12)
      - Chaplin at Home: A Week at Corsier (Box 34)
      - The Chaplin Film Greets the World (Box 34)
      - Chaplin on Filming in England (Box 34)
      - Chapter I: The One Man (Box 34)
      - Chapter II (Box 34)
      - Chapter III (Box 34)
      - Chapter IV (Box 34)
      - Chapter V (Box 34)
      - Chapter VI (Box 34)
      - Chapter VII (Box 34)
      - Charles Chaplin (Box 34)
      - The Charles Chaplin Family in Switzerland (Box 34)
      - Charlie (Box 34)
      - Charlie Chaplin (Box 34)
      - Charlot en Pantoufles (Box 34)
        (missing pages)
      - The Decision to Shoot the Pictures (Box 34)
      - Early Life (Box 34)
      - "Limelight" Reviews (Box 34)
      - Oona (Box 34)
      - Oona O’Neill Chaplin and Her Marriage (Box 34)
      - The Sporting Chaplins (Box 34)
      - Trip to Switzerland (Box 34)
    - Subseries IV.3.5: Modern African Art
      - Art from Africa, Undated (Box 39)
      - Modern African Art (Box 39)
  - Subseries IV.4: Miscellaneous; Documents
    - Manuscripts
      - Notes
        - Notes (Box 17, 39)
        - "Carmel" (Box 39)
        - "Made in America: (Box 39)
      - Notes and Fragments, Typescript (Box 17)
      - Unidentified (Box 17)
        (probably by Ella Winter)
      - By Others
        - General (Box 17)
        - About Ella Winter (Box 17)
    - Documents
      - General (Box 17)
      - Datebook, 1962 (Box 17)
      - Financial (Box 17)
      - Hospital Stay Notes (Box 39)
      - Medical (Box 17)
      - Passports (Box 40)
        (Three passports for Ella Winter)
      - "People’s Platform" (Box 39)
        (Transcript)
      - Printed--Clippings (Box 39)
      - Unidentified (Box 39)
      - Untitled (Box 39)
      - "Win with Wooster" (Author Unknown) (Box 39)
- Series V: Subject Files
  The subject files include clippings, correspondence, ephemera, manuscripts (by others), and printed material. The correspondence in the subject files is either about the subject, or, in the case of some persons, includes correspondence between the subject and persons other than Ella Winter.
  - Anderson, Edward--Thieves Like Us (Box 36)
    (Full Typescript)
  - Art
    - General (Box 18)
    - Photographs, (6 Folders) (Box 18, 36)
    - Portrait Photographs, Undated (Box 36)
    - Printed
      - General (Box 18)
      - Catalogues and Exhibition Notices, (2 folders) (Box 18)
  - Berreman, Gerald D.--"Is Anthropology Alive", Undated (Box 36)
    (Typescript)
  - California Labor
    (Migrants, Strikes, etc.)
    - Correspondence (Box 19)
    - General (Box 19)
    - Notes (Box 19)
    - Printed (Box 19)
  - Chaplin, Charlie
    - "A King in New York"--Press Reviews, 1957 (Box 34)
    - Chaplin Family--Clippings (Box 41)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1964 (Box 34)
    - "Extracts from the Script: The King in New York" (Box 35)
    - Notes and Typescript (Box 35)
    - Notes, Texts and Fragments, Typescript (Box 35)
    - Photographs and Drawings (Box 35)
    - Printed Material
      - General, 1957 1964 (Box 35)
      - Clippings (Box 35)
      - The Leaping Lad and Other Stories, by Sid Chaplin (Box 35)
      - My Wonderful Visit, by Charlie Chaplin (Box 35)
  - China
    - Correspondence (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 39)
    - Communiqués and Releases (Box 19)
    - Herbarium (leaf scrapbook) (Box 19)
    - Medicine and Health (Box 19)
    - Notebooks (Box 20)
      (Volumes. 1-8, 10-13 and four unnumbered)
    - Notebooks
      - Loose materials (Box 20)
      - Typescript copies (Box 20)
    - Notes, Manuscript (Box 20)
    - Notes and texts, Typescript (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20)
    - Photographs
      - Aged (Box 21)
      - Alley, Rewi (Box 21)
      - Animals (Box 21)
      - Art and Culture (Box 21)
      - Children (Box 21)
      - Chungking (Box 21)
      - Collectives, Communes and Farmers (Box 21)
      - Entertainment (Box 21)
      - Exhibitions (Box 21)
      - Family Life (Box 21)
      - Hangchov (Box 21)
      - Hankow (Box 21)
      - Huhehot (See Also: Inner Mongolia) (Box 21)
      - Inner Mongolia (Box 21)
      - Kunming and vicinity (Box 21)
      - Murals and Posters (Box 21)
      - Parades and Demonstrations (Box 21)
      - Parks, Gardens and Zoos (Box 21)
      - Peking (Box 21)
      - Picture Books and Packets (Box 21)
      - Rat-catcher (Tsao I Hsiu) (Box 21)
      - Religion (Box 21)
      - Science and Medicine (Box 21)
      - Shanghai (Box 21)
      - Structures (Box 21)
      - Towns, Unidentified (Box 22)
      - Transport (Box 22)
      - "Under Tea Wood" (essay, q.v.)--Illustrations (Box 22)
      - With Ella Winter (Box 22)
      - Women (Box 22)
      - Workers (Box 22)
      - Miscellaneous, unidentified; negatives; lists (Box 22)
    - Printed
      - Art and Cultures (Box 22)
      - Articles by Ella Winter (Box 22)
      - Children's Literature (Box 23)
      - Clippings (Box 23)
      - "I Met a China Capitalist," 1959 (Box 39)
      - "The Emperor Wan-Li Returns to China," 1959 (Box 39)
      - Maps (Box 23)
      - Politics and Sociology (Box 23)
      - 1 oversized folder, containing primarily Chinese posters (Box Oversized Folder)
  - Ghana
    - Correspondence (Box 24)
    - Documents (Box 24)
    - Fact Sheets (Box 24)
    - Films (Box 24)
    - Invitations and Programmes (Box 24)
    - Notes, Manuscripts (Box 24)
    - Notes, Texts and Fragments, Typescript (Box 24)
    - Stewart, Donald Ogden (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 25)
    - Photographs (Box 25)
    - Printed (Box 25)
      - General (Box 25)
      - Maps (Box 25)
      - Periodicals and Pamphlets (Box 25)
  - Gilliatt, Penelope--Manuscripts--A State of Change (Box 40)
  - Hochhuth, Rolf--Manuscripts--"Soldiers," circa 1960s (Box 41)
    (With notes and related items)
  - Jeffers, Robinson and Una (Box 25)
  - Leicester, William F--Manuscripts--"The Marble Faun" (Box 40)
    (Script Treatment)
  - McCarthy Era
    - Correspondence, Hearings, etc. (Box 26)
    - Printed (Box 26)
  - Middle East (Box 26)
  - Modern African Art
    - Correspondence
      - A-D, 1965-1971 (Box 36)
      - E-K, 1966-1978 (Box 37)
      - L-N, 1968-1980 (Box 37)
      - O-P, 1968-1979 (Box 37)
      - R-S, 1968-1974 (Box 37)
      - T-W, 1968-1971 (Box 37)
      - Dated (Writers Unknown), 1969-1970 (Box 37)
      - Unidentified (Writers and Dates Unknown) (Box 37)
    - Catalogs and Exhibition Notices, 1965-1971 (Box 37)
    - Notes and Typescripts (Box 38)
    - Photographs
      - General, Undated (Box 38)
      - Ulli Beier and family, circa 1960s (Box 38)
    - Poetry (Unknown Writers), Undated (Box 38)
    - Printed--Clippings, 1964-1970 (Box 38)
  - Russia
    - Correspondence, Notes and Drafts (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 26)
    - Photographs
      - General (Box 26)
      - Death Camp, Estonia, circa 1945 (Box 26)
    - Printed
      - By Ella Winter (Box 27)
      - General (Box 27)
  - Steffens, Lincoln
    - Correspondence (Box 27)
    - Correspondence (Box 27)
      (copies of Steffens' letters)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1933 (Box 38)
    - Manuscripts about Steffens by others (Box 27)
    - Notes, Manuscript and Typescript (Box 27)
    - Obituary Notices, 1936 (Box 38)
    - Papers of Steffens, Winter, D.O. Stewart (Box 27)
      (Columbia, Yale)
    - Steffens’ works (Box 28)
      ((copies, for World of Lincoln Steffens and Lincoln Steffens Speaking )
    - Autobiography (Box 28)
      (Related Materials)
    - Boy on Horseback (Box 28)
    - Lincoln Steffens by Justin Kaplan (Box 28)
    - Selected Letters, Herbert Shapiro, editor (Box 28)
    - The World of Lincoln Steffens (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 28)
    - Printed
      - Broadsides (Box 28)
      - Carmel, California--Papers (Box 28)
    - Clippings (Box 29)
      (Including review of Steffens’ works)
    - Death of Steffens (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous (Loose) (Box 29)
  - Steffens, Pete Stanley and family
    - Correspondence
      - A-G, 1948-1973 (Box 38)
      - H, 1948-1968 (Box 38)
      - I-R, 1947-1950 (Box 39)
      - S-Z, 1948-1971 (Box 39)
      - Dated Correspondence (Writers Unknown), 1931-1968 (Box 39)
      - Unidentified Correspondence (Writers and Dates Unknown) (Box 39)
    - Journalism Documents, 1969-1973 (Box 40)
    - Navy Ensign Appointment, 1946 (Box 40)
  - Stewart, Donald Odgen
    - Correspondence
      - 1950-1978 (Box 40)
      - Dated Correspondence (Writers Unknown), 1952-1958 (Box 40)
      - Unidentified Correspondence, (Writers and Dates Unknown), 1952-1958 (Box 40)
    - Manuscripts--"The Kidders" (Box 40)
    - Talk--"Accepting Happiness Very Bravely" (Box 40)
  - U.S.S.R.--Correspondence, 1958 (Box 40)
  - Vietnam (Box 30)
  - Vidor, King--Manuscript--Scripts (and related materials) (Box 40)
- Series VI: Photographs and Miscellaneous
  - Photographs
    - General (Box 30)
    - Austria, ca. 1920 (Box 30)
    - Theatre (Box 30)
    - Unidentified Negatives (Box 40)
      (One set of 19 negatives that appears to be primarily family photographs)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 30)